Guide to the Malvern Hill Omohundro Papers, 1866-1926 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
Malvern Hill Omohundro papers 1866-1926 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
Omohundro, Malvern Hill, b. 1866.
18.9 Linear Feet 14,143 Items
Lawyer, merchant, real estate agent, poultry farmer, and sawmill businessman, of Radford, Roanoke, and Richmond, Va.
Business papers, together with correspondence relating to a book Omohundro intended to write, and a diary of a student at Hollins College. Subjects include land acquisition in Virginia, the government of Richmond, and farming problems.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Malvern Hill Omohundro Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a purchase in 1954.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Omohundro, Malvern Hill, b. 1866
Hollins College -- Students.
Agriculture -- Virginia
Land settlement -- Virginia
Universities and colleges -- Virginia
Richmond (Va.) -- Politics and government
Contents of Collection
- Correspondence Series, 1866-1926 and undated, (20 boxes)
  - 1866-1899 (Box 1)
  - 1900 Jan.-Aug. (Box 2)
  - 1902-1903 (Box 3)
  - 1901 June-Dec. (Box 4)
  - 1904-1905 (Box 5)
  - 1904-1905 (Box 6)
  - 1906-1907 Oct. (Box 7)
  - 1907 Nov.-1909 Aug. (Box 8)
  - 1909 Sept.-1910 Aug. (Box 9)
  - 1910 Sept.-1911 June (Box 10)
  - 1911 July-Dec. (Box 11)
  - 1912 Jan.-June (Box 12)
  - 1912 July-1913 May (Box 13)
  - 1913 June-1914 May (Box 14)
  - 1914 June-Dec. (Box 15)
  - 1915-1916 Feb. (Box 16)
  - 1916 Mar.-Dec. (Box 17)
  - 1917-1921 (Box 18)
  - 1922-1924 (Box 19)
  - 1925-1926 and undated (Box 20)
- Legal Papers Series, (1 box)
  - Legal papers (Box 21)
- Miscellany Series, (1 box)
  - Miscellaneous materials (Box 21)
- Professional Papers Series, 1907-1919, (3 boxes)
  - 1907 (Box 22)
  - 1917-1919 (Box 23-24)
- Bound Manuscripts
  - Volume (Volume M:6729)